// Requiring necessary npm packages
var express = require("express");
var session = require("express-session");
var exphbs = require("express-handlebars");
const Handlebars = require("handlebars");
var {
  allowInsecurePrototypeAccess
} = require("@handlebars/allow-prototype-access");

// Requiring passport as we've configured it
var passport = require("./config/passport");

// Setting up port and requiring models for syncing
var PORT = process.env.PORT || 8080;
var db = require("./models");

// Creating express app and configuring middleware needed for authentication
var app = express();
app.use(express.urlencoded({ extended: true }));
app.use(express.json());
app.use(express.static("public"));
// We need to use sessions to keep track of our user's login status
app.use(
  session({ secret: "keyboard cat", resave: true, saveUninitialized: true })
);
app.use(passport.initialize());
app.use(passport.session());

app.engine(
  "handlebars",
  exphbs({
    defaultLayout: "main",
    handlebars: allowInsecurePrototypeAccess(Handlebars)
  })
);
app.set("view engine", "handlebars");

// Requiring our routes
require("./controllers/html-routes.js")(app);
require("./controllers/api-routes.js")(app);

// Syncing our database and logging a message to the user upon success
db.sequelize
  .sync({ force: true })
  .then(() => {
    // STRING ============================
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 1,
      question: "Find the length of  the 'str'variable.",
      code: "var str = 'ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZ'",
      label: "var strLength = ",
      answer: "str.length;",
      category: "string_methods",
      next: "/members/string_methods/2"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 2,
      question: "Find the index of 'locate' within the 'str' variable.",
      code: "var str= 'Please locate where 'locate' occurs!'",
      label: "var position = ",
      answer: "str.indexOf('locate');",
      category: "string_methods",
      next: "/members/string_methods/3"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 3,
      question: "Slice 'Banana' from the 'str' variable",
      code: "var str= 'Apple, Banana, Kiwi';",
      label: "var results = ",
      answer: "str.slice(7,13);",
      category: "string_methods",
      next: "/members/string_methods/4"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 4,
      question: "Replace 'Hello' with 'Goodbye' in the 'str' variable.",
      code: "var str ='Hello World';",
      label: "var newStr =",
      answer: "str.replace('Hello','Goodbye');",
      category: "string_methods",
      next: "/members/string_methods/5"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 5,
      question: "Convert the 'str' variable into all uppercase letters.",
      code: "var str= 'hello world'",
      label: "var uppercaseStr =",
      answer: "str.toUpperCase();",
      category: "string_methods",
      next: "/members/string_methods/6"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 6,
      question: "Convert the 'str' variable into all lowercase letters.",
      code: "var str = 'HELLO WORLD';",
      label: "var lowercaseStr =",
      answer: "str.toLowerCase();",
      category: "string_methods",
      next: "/members/string_methods/7"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 7,
      question: "Find the character at index 0 in the 'str' variable",
      code: "var str ='Hello World';",
      label: "var indexZero = ",
      answer: "str.charAt(0);",
      category: "string_methods",
      next: "/members/string_methods/8"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 8,
      question: "Convert the ‚Äústr‚Äù variable into an array using the ‚Äú,‚Äù.",
      code: "var str = ‚Äúa,b,c,d,e,f,g,h‚Äù;",
      label: "var strArray =",
      answer: "str.split(‚Äú,‚Äù);",
      category: "string_methods",
      next: "/members/number_methods/1"
    });
    // NUMBER ============================
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 1,
      question: "Convert the 'num' variable into a string.",
      code: "var num = 123;",
      label: "var numString = ",
      answer: "num.toString();",
      category: "number_methods",
      next: "/members/number_methods/2"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 2,
      question: "Give the 'num' variable a fixed amount of 2 decimal places.",
      code: "var num = 9.656;",
      label: "var fixedNum = ",
      answer: "num.toFixed(2);",
      category: "number_methods",
      next: "/members/number_methods/3"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 3,
      question: "Parse the 'txt' variable and convert it to a number.",
      code: "var txt = '10';",
      label: "var num = ",
      answer: "parseInt(txt);",
      category: "number_methods",
      next: "/members/array_methods/1"
    });
    // ARRAY ============================
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 1,
      question:
        "use the correct array method to remove the last item of the fruits array",
      code: "var fruits = ['Banana','Orange','Apple'];",
      label: null,
      answer: "fruits.pop();",
      category: "array_methods",
      next: "/members/array_methods/2"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 2,
      question: "Convert the 'fruits' variable to a string",
      code: "var fruits =['Banana','Orange','Apple', 'Mango'];",
      label: "var fruitString =",
      answer: "fruits.toString();",
      category: "array_methods",
      next: "/members/array_methods/3"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 3,
      question:
        "use the correct Array method to sort the fruits array alphabetically",
      code: "var fruits =['Banana','Orange','Apple', 'Kiwi'];",
      label: null,
      answer: "fruits.sort();",
      category: "array_methods",
      next: "/members/array_methods/4"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 4,
      question: "Concatenate ‚Äúarray1‚Äù and ‚Äúarray2‚Äù",
      code:
        "var array1 = ['Cecilie', 'Lone'];<br>var array2 = ['Emil', 'Tobias', 'Linus'];",
      label: "bothArrays =",
      answer: "array1.concat(array2);",
      category: "array_methods",
      next: "/members/array_methods/5"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 5,
      question: "Get the value ‚ÄúVolvo‚Äù from the cars array",
      code: "var cars = [‚ÄúSaab‚Äù, ‚ÄúVolvo‚Äù, ‚ÄúBMW‚Äù];",
      label: "var x =",
      answer: "var x = cars[1];",
      category: "array_methods",
      next: "/members/array_methods/6"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 6,
      question: "Change the first item of cars to ‚ÄúFord‚Äù",
      code: "var cars = [‚ÄúVolvo‚Äù, ‚ÄúJeep‚Äù, ‚ÄúMercedes‚Äù];",
      label: "-------- = ‚ÄúFord‚Äù;",
      answer: "cars[0]",
      category: "array_methods",
      next: "/members/array_methods/7"
    });
    db.Question.create({
      exercise: 7,
      question:
        "Alert the number of items in an array, using the correct Array method",
      code: "var cars = [‚ÄúVolvo‚Äù,‚ÄùJeep‚Äù,‚ÄùMercedes‚Äù];",
      label: "alert(------------------);",
      answer: "cars.length",
      category: "array_methods",
      next: "/members/module/complete"
    });
  })
  .then(function() {
    app.listen(PORT, function() {
      console.log(
        "==> üåé  Listening on port %s. Visit http://localhost:%s/ in your browser.",
        PORT,
        PORT
      );
    });
  });
